jobscan.co 2019-12-15

# Privacy Policy - Jobscan

* * *

**Effective Date: May 25, 2018**

Jobscan is committed to respecting the privacy of our users and complying with Privacy laws. We strive to provide a safe, secure user experience. This Privacy Policy sets forth the online data collection and usage policies and practices that apply to our website. By using the Jobscan website, you consent to the policies and practices described in this Statement. 

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for (www.jobscan.co). This privacy policy applies solely to information collected by this web site. 

Your data will be stored and processed in whole or in part in the United States. If you access the Jobscan website outside the United States, your usage of our site constitutes consent to the transfer of your data out of your country and into the United States. 

## COLLECTION AND RETENTION OF INFORMATION

In some areas of our websites, Jobscan requests or may request that you provide personal information, including your name, gender, address, email address, telephone number, contact information, birthdate, billing information and any other information from which your identity is discernible. Jobscan may also request that you upload a copy of your resume and connect Jobscan to your LinkedIn profile, thereby providing personal information regarding your education, prior employment, occupation, titles, and skills, as well as your most recent profile picture, the last article you may have shares, number of connections, industry information and non-specific geolocation information. 

We also gather certain information about your use of our site, such as what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that is collected by Jobscan. This information can include without limitation your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses. We gather this information automatically and store it in log files. We do not link this automatically collected date to other information we collect about you. 

Jobscan also collects, or logs, certain other information that cannot identify you personally when you visit our Sites. This information includes your Internet Protocol ("IP") address and your domain name. An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer by the ISP computer through which you access the web and a domain name is the name of the ISP computer itself through which you access the web. Jobscan logs these IP addresses and domain names and aggregates them for system administration and to monitor the use of our site. We may use the aggregated information to measure the number of visits to our site, the average time spent on our site, the number of pages viewed, and various other site use statistics. Such monitoring helps us evaluate how our Sites are used and continuously improve the content we provide. 

In addition, Jobscan may collect indirect information about you when you use certain third party services on our site. For example, if you register on our site by using your LinkedIn user name and password, you authorize us to have access to and store the information from your LinkedIn Account profile; such information will be subject to, and treated in accordance with, the policies and practices described in this Privacy Policy. 

Jobscan receives information about you from certain of its third party partners, such as Google, Facebook and LinkedIn. You may be entitled to receive a list of the specific nonaffiliated third-parties that Jobscan receives your personal data from. If you would like to view such a list, please email our support at support@jobscan.co. 

You can correct or update your Jobscan account profile, resume(s) or email alerts at any time. Moreover, you can delete your resume(s) from Jobscan 's online database or close your account(s) at any time, in which event we will remove all our copies of your resume and cover letters. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

We do not share, sell, rent or trade personal information with parties for their promotional purposes. 

Unless required by law, we do not/will not collect or process any of the following types of sensitive data: Race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union memberships, genetic or biometric data, health or mortality, or sex life or sexual orientation. 

## USE OF INFORMATION BY JOBSCAN

We use the information we gather on an Jobscan website, whether personal, demographic, collective or technical, for the purpose of operating and improving the Jobscan website, fostering a positive user experience, and delivering the products and services that we offer. We may also use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason(s) you contacted us. We may also use the information we gather to inform you of other products or services available from Jobscan. 

By registering with Jobscan, by managing your profile, or expressly opting in when presented with choices, you have consented for us to. We will use your information, subject to local law, in the following ways: to allow you to create an account; to create a profile for you based on information that you have provided to us; to contact you about site updates, informational and service-related communications, including important security updates; to provide you additional communications, information, and promotions such as newsletters and career advice; to inform you of other products or services available from Jobscan or its affiliates; to enable you to provide feedback, to contact us and for us to respond to you; to conduct surveys and questionnaires, to generate internal reports about the use of our site; and to provide ‘forward to a friend’ features. 

Unless you ask us not to, we may contact you via email in the future to tell you about resume tips, specials, new products/services, or changes to this privacy policy. The nature and frequency of these messages will vary depending upon the information we have about you. In addition, at the time of registration for Jobscan, you have the option to elect to receive additional communications, information and promotions including without limitation free informational newsletters from Jobscan relating to topics that may be of special interest to you. 

Jobscan may also provide such information to subsidiaries, affiliates and other trusted third parties with whom we have alliances in connection with providing products or services that you have requested or otherwise with your permission, subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

## DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION TO THIRD PARTIES

We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization except as provided in this Privacy Policy, other than product feedback. We will only allow your resume to be searchable to recruiters once Jobscan partners with recruiters and you opted in. Jobscan.co currently does not partner with any recruiters. 

We do not disclose to third parties your personal information for promotional purposes, combined personal and demographic information or information about your use of an Jobscan website (such as the areas you visit or the services you access), except as set forth below. 

We may disclose such information to third parties if you consent to such disclosure. For example, if you indicate that you would like to receive information about the products or services of third parties at the time you register for an Jobscan account, we may supply your contact information to third parties such as employers, recruiters, agents, brokers, dealers, data aggregators, marketers or others for the purpose of sending you email or otherwise communicating with you. If you do not want us to share your personal information with these companies, contact us at support@jobscan.co. 

We may share your information with third parties who help us in the delivery of our own products and services to you. We disclose information to companies and individuals we employ to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include hosting our web servers, analyzing data, providing marketing assistance, processing credit card payments, and providing customer service. These companies and individuals may be located in a country whose data protection legislation is different from your country, and they will have access to your personal information as necessary to perform their functions, but they may not share that information with any other third party or use that data for any other purpose. We will remain the data controller and be responsible for any information shared in this way. 

We may disclose such information if legally required to do so, if requested to do so by a governmental entity or if we believe in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (b) protect the rights or property of Jobscan or its affiliated companies; (c) prevent a crime or protect national security; or (d) protect the personal safety of users or the public. 

We may disclose and transfer such information to a third party who acquires all or a substantial portion of Jobscan's business, whether such acquisition is by way of merger, consolidation or purchase of all or a substantial portion of our assets. In addition, in the event Jobscan becomes the subject of a bankruptcy proceeding, whether voluntary or involuntary, Jobscan or its trustee in bankruptcy may sell, license or otherwise dispose of such information in a transaction approved by the bankruptcy court. If such event occurs we will display a prominent notice on our website. 

Jobscan may also share aggregated anonymous information about visitors to our websites with our clients, partners and other third parties so that they may understand the kinds of visitors to Jobscan's site and how those visitors use the site. 

## THIRD PARTY ADVERTISERS

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. 

The ads appearing on this Web site are delivered to users by Google AdSense, our advertising partner. We share Web site usage information about users with a reputable third party Google AdSense for the purpose of targeting our Internet banner advertisements on this site. Google AdSense uses cookies and clear GIFs on this site, which allow it to recognize a user's cookie when a user visits this site. The information that Google AdSense collects and shares through this technology is not personally identifiable. 

You may opt-out of the use of this cookie by visiting Google's Advertising and Privacy page: http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html. 

Jobscan uses a tool called “Google Analytics”, and its "Display Advertising", "Remarketing" and "Demographics and Interest Reporting" features. We use Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. Third-party vendors, including Google, may show you ads on sites across the internet. We and third party vendors, including Google, use first party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based upon your past visits to our site. We use Demographics and Interest Reporting to obtain demographic data of our users including a user’s age, gender, language, and interests. We may use this data for general marketing knowledge, and to tailor our service offerings and advertising to better meet the needs and interests of our customers. Using Google’s Ads Settings, you can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads. 

If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately via email. 

## YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR INFORMATION

Subject to any undertakings set forth in any Terms and Conditions or client service contract to which you are a party, you may withdraw your consent for the collection, use and/or disclosure of your personal data in our possession by emailing us at support@jobscan.co We will process your request within thirty days and will thereafter not collect, use and/or disclose your personal data in the manner stated in your request, unless the law permits us to. Please note, however, that under certain circumstances your withdrawal of consent could result in us being unable to provide you with access to our Platform and/or Services. 

We retain all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical and relevant [until you change or remove your personal data as described below. You may withdraw your consent for the collection, use and/or disclosure of your personal data in our possession by emailing us at support@jobscan.co. We will process your request within thirty days and will thereafter not collect, use and/or disclose your personal data in the manner stated in your request, unless the law permits us to. In addition, upon receiving such a request, and after verifying your identity, we can provide you with the following: the personal data we have collected from you; an explanation stating why we collected it; a list of who, other than us, has had access to it; if/how it is being/was used in automated decisions, and what processes of ours are/were using it. In addition, Jobscan will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. 

You may have access to, review, correct, update, change or delete your account profile information or profile/resume at any time. Simply log into your account, go to your profile/resume, and make the necessary changes. You may delete your profile/resume from Jobscan’s online database at any time by requesting a permanent removal of your information from support@jobscan.co. Before providing you with a copy of your personal information or correcting, updating or deleting such information, we reserve the right to verify and authenticate your identity and the personal information to which you have requested access. Access to or correction, updating or deletion of your personal information may be denied or limited by Jobscan if it would violate another person’s rights and/or as otherwise permitted by applicable law. We will respond to information access requests within 30 days of receipt, [and we will instruct any third-parties with whom we have shared it to erase it.] If we require additional time to provide access to your information, we will acknowledge receipt of your request within 30 days and promptly supplement our response within the time period required by applicable law. 

If you opted to receive newsletters, commercial emails or other communications from Jobscan or third parties at the time you registered with Jobscan, but subsequently change your mind, you may opt-out by editing your Account Profile as described above. If you previously opted not to receive such communications, you may later opt-in by editing your Account Profile. 

## SECURITY

Jobscan has implemented technical and organizational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorized access, use, alteration or disclosure. Notwithstanding such measures, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes. We will notify the owners of Jobscan accounts within 48 hours of the discovery of a data breach, and we will work with our customers to inform account holders who may have been directly affected by the breach. 

Moreover, one of our primary purposes is to provide you with a platform to broadcast the information in your profile/resume and profile widely and to maximize your career opportunities. Accordingly, such an environment does present a risk that unauthorized third parties will view this data. Further, your profile/resume should not contain any sensitive data including personality profiles or data that you would not want made public. 

When you place an order online at Jobscan, your credit card information is protected through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") protocol. SSL makes it difficult for your credit card information to be intercepted or stolen while being transmitted. Jobscan uses a service company to process its credit card transactions. 

We also use cookies, web beacons, and Java Script to administer our site and deliver a personalized experience. For additional detailed information on each of these, please see below. 

You are responsible for ensuring that your log-in credentials (your username and password) are kept confidential. 

## USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

Technologies such as cookies, beacons, scripts and tags are used by Jobscan and our partners, affiliates or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the website, tracking users' movements around the site, and gathering demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing these types of tracking technologies. 

We use cookies on our site to tell the web server that you have returned to a specific page. For example, if you personalize Jobscan pages, or register for services, a cookie helps us to recall your specific information (such as user name, password and preferences). We also use cookies of certain third party partners, including Indeed.com, Hotjar and Mixpanel, which have plugins installed on our site. 

Because of our use of cookies, we can deliver faster and more accurate results and a more personalized site experience. When you return to the Jobscan site, the information you previously provided can be retrieved, so you can easily use the features that you customized. We also use cookies to track click streams and for load balancing. 

You may have the ability to accept or decline Jobscan and/or third party cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline all cookies if you prefer. Alternatively, you may be able to modify your browser setting to notify you each time a cookie is tendered and permit you to accept or decline cookies on an individual basis. If you choose to decline cookies, however, that may hinder performance and negatively impact your experience on the Jobscan website. To protect your privacy, be sure to close your browser completely after you have finished conducting business with a website that does use cookies. 

## HOW WE RESPOND TO DO NOT TRACK SIGNALS

Online tracking is the collection of data about an individual’s Internet activity used to deliver targeted advertisements and for other purposes. Customers using certain modern browsers have the ability to activate a “Do Not Track” signal. Jobscan does not currently respond to the “Do Not Track” signal. 

## THIRD PARTIES

Our site contains links to other websites over which we have no control. Jobscan is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of other websites to which you choose to link from the Jobscan website. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of those other websites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information. This Privacy Policy applies solely to the information we collect on the Jobscan website, and does not apply to information we collect in any other fashion. 

## YOUR CALIFORNIA RIGHTS

A California resident who has provided personal information to a business with whom he/she has established a business relationship for personal, family, or household purposes (“California customer”) is entitled to request information about whether the business has disclosed personal information to any third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes. In general, if the business has made such a disclosure of personal information, upon receipt of a request by a California customer, the business is required to provide a list of all third parties to whom personal information was disclosed in the preceding calendar year, as well as a list of the categories of personal information that were disclosed. 

However, under the law, a business is not required to provide the above-described lists if the business adopts and discloses to the public (in its privacy policy) a policy of not disclosing customer’s personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless the customer first affirmatively agrees to the disclosure, as long as the business maintains and discloses this policy. Rather, the business may comply with the law by notifying the customer of his or her right to prevent disclosure of personal information and providing a cost free means to exercise that right. 

We do not share information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes unless you affirmatively agree to such disclosure. If you do ask us to share your information with a third party for its marketing purposes, we will only share information in connection with that specific promotion, as we do not share information with any third party on a continual basis. To prevent disclosure of your personal information for use in direct marketing by a third party, do not opt in to such use when you provide personally identifiable information on one of our sites. Please note that whenever you opt in to receive future communications from a third party, your information will be subject to the third party's privacy policy. If you later decide that you do not want that third party to use your information, you will need to contact the third party directly, as we have no control over how third parties use information. You should always review the privacy policy of any party that collects your information to determine how that entity will handle your information. 

California customers may request further information about our compliance with this law by e-mailing us at support@jobscan.co. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address. 

## CHILDREN

Jobscan is not intended for children under 16 years of age. We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. 

## CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and all updates will be posted on this page so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and to whom we will disclose it. 

## QUESTIONS

If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please visit our FAQ page to discover the many ways in which you can reach us.
